MOHAMED AMMAR

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Recent coding Bootcamp graduate, MBA holder, and a former banker with 9 years of financial experience, seeking a career opportunity as a Jr. Software Developer in order to start gaining professional experience and adding value to Phone: (415) 889-3925 the company and myself

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration (MBA), Finance, 11/2020 Lincoln University - Oakland, CA

Full-Stack Software Development Certification, Web Development, 11/2020 Suncoast Developers Guild - St. Petersburg, FL

A 14 weeks Immersive Full-Stack web development program that teaches clientside (front-end) technology: HTML, CSS, Javascript and React as well as serverside (back-end) technology which includes C#, .NET and SQL Databases

Bachelor of Commerce, Accounting & Business Management, 07/2007 Zagazig University - Egypt

PROJECTS

Portfolio: mohamedammar.com

Mo's Kitchen

http://mokitchen.herokuapp.com/

A web-based full-stack food recipes application built using ReactJS, C#, .NET & PostgreSQL. Users can view other users' recipes and add their own after registering. In addition to building my own REST API for this, I fetched from a remote API server to view additional recipes on the landing page.

Taco Resuarant Finder

https://mytacos.netlify.app/

Demo: https://youtu.be/FNGspnjJJJ8

A Frontend ReactJs app created created using Yelp's API to list all the Taco restaurants in a given city and displays the details of a restaurant selected

Yelp's API does not allow CORS so a proxy with CORS support using glitch.me was set up to return data from two of Yelp's endpoints.

Color Picker

https://color-picker-moammar.netlify.app/

A front-end single-page web-based application built using ReactJS that allows developers to pick their own HSL-based colors, the App is simple but I am proud of it since I made it with my own ReactJS knowledge even before I start learning React indepth at my SDG cohort.

CONTACT

Address: Tampa, FL 33634 (willing to relocate)

Email:

Mohamed.ammar86@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mammar86 GitHub: github.com/mammar86 Webpage: mohamedammar.com

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- C#
- .NET
- APIs
- PostgreSQL
- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- Git
- GitHub
- JQuery
- Finance & Management

Currency Converter

https://currency-converter-moammar.netlify.app

A currency converter app that was built using ReactJS as I fetched from a remote API server to update the currencies exchange rate, I built it as an assignment and there is a big room to improve it in the future

WORK HISTORY

Relationship Banker, 01/2020 to 08/2020 Synovus Financial Corp. - Clearwater, FL

Achieved my quarterly sales target during the first month of hiring.

Personal Banker, 04/2018 to 01/2019 Citibank - San Francisco, CA

Successfully ran the branch operations on my own as there was no manager for over 3 months also still achieved my sales target

Relationship Banker, 02/2017 to 03/2018 Bank of America - San Francisco, CA

Personal Banker, 07/2009 to 05/2016 Qatar National Bank - Mansoura, Egypt

Constantly ranked among the Top-Ten nationally recognized for customer service level also sales target